

Profile

Experienced and driven Financial Analyst with an impressive background of managing multi-million dollar budgets while providing analysis and account support within product development departments. Worked to reduce business expenses and develop logical and advantageous operating plan budgets. Experience creating quarterly accruals based on trends and forecasted expenses.

Employment History

Financial Analyst at GEO Corp., New York

October 2012 - September 2019

- Created budgets and ensured that labor and material costs were decreased by 15 percent.
- Created financial reports on completed projects, indicating advantageous results.
- Generated financial statements including cash flow charts and balance sheets.
- Created analysis and performance reports for management teams to review.
- Introduced and implemented a different type of innovative software.
- Assessed new development projects generating over \$4.5M in revenue.

Financial Analyst at Sisco Enterprises, New York

September 2008 — September 2012

- Provided reports, ad-hoc analysis, annual operating plan budgets, monthly cash forecasts, and revenue forecasts.
- Analyzed supplier contracts and advised in negotiations bringing budgets down by 6%.
- Created weekly labor finance reports and presented the results to management.
- Modeled anticipated revenue charts to accurately track our progress in relation to forecasts and intentions.

Education

Bachelor of Finance, Villanova University, King of Prussia

August 2004 - May 2008

Graduated suma cum laude.

High School Diploma, Camden High School, Camden

September 2000 — June 2004

■ References

Devin Strazza from GEO Corp.

Details

333 Oklahoma Road New York, NY 10024 United States (917) 407-5112 Mj12@gmail.com

Skills

Financial Analysis

Strategic Planning

Trend Analysis

Market Assessment

Team Leadership

Languages

Spanish